<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Java on Enoch Sun</title>
        <link>https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/tags/java/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Java on Enoch Sun</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Enoch Sun</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Concert Booking System: Simplifying Ticket Reservations</title>
        <link>https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/p/concert-booking-system-simplifying-ticket-reservations/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/p/concert-booking-system-simplifying-ticket-reservations/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/p/concert-booking-system-simplifying-ticket-reservations/concert-booking-icon.png" alt="Featured image of post Concert Booking System: Simplifying Ticket Reservations" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;concert-booking-system-simplifying-ticket-reservations-&#34;&gt;Concert Booking System: Simplifying Ticket Reservations 🎟️
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;concert-booking-screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Concert Booking System Screenshot&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project Overview
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Concert Booking System&lt;/strong&gt; is a Java-based web service designed to simplify ticket reservations for concerts. Built with scalability and performance in mind, this project showcases my backend development skills, focusing on efficiency and reliability in high-demand scenarios such as concert ticket sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concert and Performer Information:&lt;/strong&gt; Users can browse and explore details about concerts, performers, and schedules without logging in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interactive Seat Map:&lt;/strong&gt; Visualize seat availability in real-time and reserve seats directly through the interface.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure Authentication:&lt;/strong&gt; Users can log in with token-based authentication to view and manage their bookings securely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Double-Booking Prevention:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensures only one user can book a specific seat for a given concert at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notifications for Sell-Out Events:&lt;/strong&gt; Users can subscribe to updates for concerts nearing full booking capacity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;planned-features&#34;&gt;Planned Features
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current version of the &lt;strong&gt;Concert Booking System&lt;/strong&gt; is fully functional, but I plan to enhance it with the following features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Ticket Pricing:&lt;/strong&gt; Support for unique ticket prices for each concert.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-Venue Support:&lt;/strong&gt; Manage events across multiple venues with distinct layouts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hold Reservations:&lt;/strong&gt; Allow users to temporarily reserve seats during the checkout process to avoid losing selections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-demonstration&#34;&gt;Project Demonstration
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a short video showcasing the features and functionality of the &lt;strong&gt;Concert Booking System&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;video controls width=&#34;700&#34;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#34;concert-booking-demo.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
  &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;explore-the-code&#34;&gt;Explore the Code
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The full project code, along with resources such as photos and concert information provided by the university, is available as a downloadable ZIP file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;project-project-36-submission.zip&#34; &gt;👉 Download the Concert Booking System Code (ZIP)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-this-project-matters&#34;&gt;Why This Project Matters
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Concert Booking System&lt;/strong&gt; highlights my:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backend Development Expertise:&lt;/strong&gt; Proficiency in designing RESTful APIs, implementing secure authentication, and managing database consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalability Skills:&lt;/strong&gt; Designing a system capable of handling concurrent users and heavy traffic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem-Solving Abilities:&lt;/strong&gt; Overcoming challenges like double-bookings, real-time seat availability, and efficient seat reservation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creativity and Collaboration:&lt;/strong&gt; Delivering a well-rounded solution that meets both user needs and technical requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a developer with a strong technical foundation and a passion for solving real-world challenges, let’s &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:sunyike880@gmail.com&#34; &gt;connect&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Gold Miner: A Classic Java Game</title>
        <link>https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/p/gold-miner-a-classic-java-game/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/p/gold-miner-a-classic-java-game/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/p/gold-miner-a-classic-java-game/gold-miner-icon.png" alt="Featured image of post Gold Miner: A Classic Java Game" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gold-miner-a-fun-and-challenging-java-game-&#34;&gt;Gold Miner: A Fun and Challenging Java Game 🎮
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;gold-miner-screenshot.png&#34; alt=&#34;Gold Miner Game Screenshot&#34; width=&#34;600&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-overview&#34;&gt;Project Overview
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gold Miner&lt;/strong&gt; is a Java-based game where players control a claw to collect gold, rocks, and other items to achieve target scores. The game is designed to test the player&amp;rsquo;s timing and decision-making skills, with increasing difficulty as they progress through levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project highlights my ability to develop engaging and functional games using &lt;strong&gt;Java Swing&lt;/strong&gt; for the GUI and modular code for extensibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variety of Items:&lt;/strong&gt; Includes gold, large rocks, small rocks, and more, each with different point values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple Levels:&lt;/strong&gt; The game becomes more challenging as players progress, with increased target scores and time limits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time and Score Mechanics:&lt;/strong&gt; Players must meet a target score within a set time to advance to the next level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple Interface:&lt;/strong&gt; The game interface is clean and functional, built using &lt;strong&gt;Java Swing&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extensibility:&lt;/strong&gt; The code is modular, making it easy to add new features like items, levels, or mechanics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;planned-features&#34;&gt;Planned Features
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the current version of &lt;strong&gt;Gold Miner&lt;/strong&gt; offers a complete gaming experience, I plan to enhance it in the future with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background Music and Sound Effects:&lt;/strong&gt; To improve player engagement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Levels and Items:&lt;/strong&gt; To increase replayability and depth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leaderboard:&lt;/strong&gt; For tracking and displaying high scores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Interactivity:&lt;/strong&gt; Adding features like power-ups and special abilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-demonstration&#34;&gt;Project Demonstration
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a short video showcasing the features and gameplay of &lt;strong&gt;Gold Miner&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;video controls width=&#34;700&#34;&gt;
    &lt;source src=&#34;gold-miner-demo.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
    Your browser does not support the video tag.
  &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;explore-the-code&#34;&gt;Explore the Code
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The full project code is available on my GitHub. Check it out to explore how the game is structured and implemented:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ENOCHSHUAI/GoldMiner&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;👉 Visit the Gold Miner GitHub Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-this-project-matters&#34;&gt;Why This Project Matters
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gold Miner&lt;/strong&gt; showcases my:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Development Skills:&lt;/strong&gt; Creating a fully functional and engaging game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proficiency in Java:&lt;/strong&gt; Using object-oriented programming and Java Swing for GUI design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Modular Design Approach:&lt;/strong&gt; Writing maintainable and extensible code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creativity:&lt;/strong&gt; Developing a game that combines logic, timing, and fun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a developer who can combine technical skills with creativity, let&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:sunyike880@gmail.com&#34; &gt;connect&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
