<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Partnerships on Enoch Sun</title>
        <link>https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/tags/partnerships/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Partnerships on Enoch Sun</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Enoch Sun</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/tags/partnerships/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Work Experience: Facilitating Partnerships</title>
        <link>https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/p/work-experience-facilitating-partnerships/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/p/work-experience-facilitating-partnerships/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/p/work-experience-facilitating-partnerships/Cooperation%20experience.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Work Experience: Facilitating Partnerships" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;During a fortunate opportunity, I was entrusted by the owner of &lt;strong&gt;Spicy 2&lt;/strong&gt;, a local restaurant, to create additional revenue streams for their business. Leveraging this trust, I initiated and facilitated collaborations between &lt;strong&gt;Spicy 2&lt;/strong&gt; and two separate businesses: &lt;strong&gt;E Force Internet Cafe&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;GIGA Internet Cafe and Script Room&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;collaboration-with-e-force-internet-cafe&#34;&gt;Collaboration with E Force Internet Cafe
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The collaboration between Spicy 2 and E Force Internet Cafe was successfully established. The partnership involved streamlining the ordering and delivery process for customers at E Force, allowing Spicy 2 to deliver meals directly to the cafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-activities&#34;&gt;Key Activities:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication Coordination:&lt;/strong&gt; Set up a WeChat group to facilitate real-time communication between the two businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agreement Drafting:&lt;/strong&gt; Created a detailed contract outlining roles, responsibilities, and payment methods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Payment Processing:&lt;/strong&gt; Implemented a mobile EFTPOS system for seamless customer payments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;outcome&#34;&gt;Outcome:
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This partnership provided E Force customers with convenient meal options while increasing Spicy 2&amp;rsquo;s sales and market visibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;collaboration-attempt-with-giga-internet-cafe&#34;&gt;Collaboration Attempt with GIGA Internet Cafe
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite efforts to establish a similar collaboration with GIGA Internet Cafe, the partnership did not materialize due to insufficient customer traffic at GIGA. While the agreement was well-structured, the lack of consistent demand rendered the collaboration unviable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-responsibilities-and-skills-demonstrated&#34;&gt;Key Responsibilities and Skills Demonstrated
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Negotiation and Mediation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitated discussions between parties to ensure mutual satisfaction with the collaboration terms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contract Drafting:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Produced bilingual contracts that clearly defined the terms of the partnership, including delivery logistics and revenue sharing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem-Solving:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Addressed logistical challenges such as delivery timelines and payment processing to streamline operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Assessment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluated the feasibility of partnerships based on customer demand and business viability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;outcome-and-learning&#34;&gt;Outcome and Learning
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The collaboration with E Force Internet Cafe successfully increased Spicy 2&amp;rsquo;s revenue and expanded its customer base. Although the partnership with GIGA Internet Cafe did not succeed, the experience taught me the importance of assessing market conditions and demand before pursuing business relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This experience enhanced my skills in business negotiation, communication, and problem-solving while demonstrating my ability to create mutually beneficial partnerships that drive growth and profitability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contracts-i-created&#34;&gt;Contracts I Created
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are the contracts I drafted for the collaborations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;contracts/spicy2-e-force-contract.pdf&#34; &gt;Spicy 2 x E Force Internet Cafe Contract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This contract outlines the terms, responsibilities, and payment structure for the successful partnership with E Force Internet Cafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;contracts/spicy2-giga-draft-contract.pdf&#34; &gt;Spicy 2 x GIGA Internet Cafe Draft Contract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Although this collaboration did not materialize, the draft highlights the proposed partnership structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;contracts/general-collaboration-template.pdf&#34; &gt;General Collaboration Template&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A reusable template I created to streamline the drafting process for future business partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contract-gallery&#34;&gt;Contract Gallery
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you prefer to view contracts directly on this page, click on the thumbnails below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/contracts/spicy2-e-force-contract-thumbnail.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Spicy 2 x E Force Contract&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/contracts/spicy2-giga-draft-contract-thumbnail.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Spicy 2 x GIGA Draft Contract&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ENOCHSHAUI.github.io/contracts/general-collaboration-template-thumbnail.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;General Collaboration Template&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-access-the-contracts&#34;&gt;How to Access the Contracts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PDF Links:&lt;/strong&gt; Click on the links above to download and view each contract in PDF format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-Page Previews:&lt;/strong&gt; If thumbnails are linked to large images or embedded PDF viewers, you can also view them directly within your browser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section demonstrates my ability to create professional contracts tailored to business needs, ensuring clear communication and alignment between stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
